Okay Ella, we are very excited to hear more about your program and how CLO has been used.
Now I'm handing it over to you, you can start whenever you are ready.
Thank you very much.
Okay, so hello everyone, I'm Ella Sharp, I'm the course leader for the MA Innovative Fashion
Production course, which I'm sure you've had all the intros, but I've got it on my
text so I'll do it again, LCF, which is part of the University of the Arts London.
And thank you CLO3D for inviting me to talk to you today.
I'm actually going to talk about how we use CLO in the MA IFP course, which is probably
not the full range that many other people use, but we use it for very specific reasons.
So, below you can see my contact details.
I just want to explain, we use the wide range of functions in CLO3D, and it means that there
are a variety of teams from buying and marketing to design and product development.
And they all use the software differently, but they are interconnected.
And on the MA IFP, we research into and develop strategies to connect their diversities.
Thank you.
And we have a really good relationship with the
product development team.
And I'm going to turn it over to you, CLO3D.
Thank you.
this particular slide you can see a range of products and how we integrate them into tech
packs and tracking documents and this work was a group project where students had to create a
capsule collection for a brand extension where they shared the color and materials palettes
and they made digital and physical samples they also had to cost garments and think about how
much they were going to put into production and the balance the merchandising both from a brand
to customer folk fake focus but also from a brand to the manufacturing phase um and in the following
stuff that are essential in the prototyping and manufacturing of clothing now you can see here
that we have moved away from using cats we're not using cats anymore we're moving directly
into obj files um this is a bit of a hybrid um sometimes we send obj files to the factory so they
can actually look inside the garments to see how for example a facing might be stitched to the
lining and we're working towards creating accurate digital samples which the factories can work from
physically so the idea being that factories can look inside the digital version and think oh
that's how they want it made
and make make the garments and when we're constructing digital samples in clo3d we have to
cut the patterns and sew them digitally differently to physical assembling process so this is complex
and does require a strong understanding of physical construction methods to interrogate the accuracy
of the digital sample otherwise the physical piece won't fit so we have to be able to understand
how to construct samples digitally and physically because when we make them
we've got to consider the particle distance obviously and layering process to stop linings
for example popping through the outer layer of the garments not something a conventional
pattern cutter or design studio would have to think about they'd have to think about
it in the physical context but not necessarily from a drawing perspective so when we're making
We're thinking digitally and physically simultaneously.
Our course focuses on all the information teams need to get a concept to the shop floor
and end of life.
And this is how the product can be, for example, repurposed or recycled.
We really use Clo3D to help us visualize this.
It's really important to us.
The fashion industry really needs to change rapidly in response, we believe, to the decades
of practice that's created a linear approach, disconnecting the manufacture and retailing
apparel.
At LCF, we are really everything that the climate crisis is here and that underpins
all of our teaching and our understanding of how the fashion industry needs to innovate
and evolve, but rapidly, and we've got to change the way we make and consume clothing.
We need to reduce environmental impact.
It's essential, not only in the physical production of clothing, but also in digital options.
Sometimes we have virtual fashion, metaverse brands discussing or saying that virtual fashion
is so much more sustainable than physical fashion.
But there are a lot of different ways of doing that.
And I think that's really important.
There are a lot of energy and precious metals, in and environmental impact, you know, with
mining for precious metals, for battery, storing digital files.
So it's not straightforward.
But here I wanted to show you something that Jai has created.
This is one of our recent graduates, she created a full length coat, and her whole business
model was to create a full length coat.
create a disassembly and reconstruction system into the range of garments the
business model is based on take back modular principle meaning that the
customers send back their garments and the business model envisages the
repurposing the panels as the garments wear out using is actually this is a
really good version or a really good example of how Jai envisaged the Ellen
MacArthur foundation butterfly diagram and how she actually included it in her
business model and the way that she disassembled garments but before she
disassembled them she designed them essential to this is the use of close 3d
to show the factories and the customers how the garments can be remade into new
garments because people can't always visualize how something would look we
really really enjoy this it's quite challenging I think sometimes
they don't know what they're doing and they don't know what they're doing and
the students find it a bit of a like oh my goodness we've done this it looks
good visually and I'm saying yes but what does it look like inside and here
you can see Jen Jan's business model and she's replaced some of the physical
processes in the production amendment phases along the top so if you look
along the top you can see conventional bespoke sort of point of sale to
delivery with the customer and on the bottom
you can see how she's reimagined that using or integrating digital
prototyping and for this project Jen invested investigated bespoke clothing
making on-demand and to an individual specification which closed 3d is well
suited I have got her film I've got three short clips of film at the end of
this presentation showing you how our students use code 3d within their
master's projects so if you're interested in learning more about the
course you can click on the link in the description below so here you can see
her flow throughs and also attention to avatar so we do on our on our probe on
our course we do a lot of work which investigates body scanning and avatar
editing and the reason being that if we consider high street clothing you know
30% of products don't sell and a lot of returns the primary reason for returns
is that they don't fit accurately so we're really working hard at creating
accurate avatars and here you can see how Jen had investigated different ways
of collecting data to create avatars I mean all software programs have their
limitations and for us some of the physical tailoring measurements are
missing in the code 3d avatar editor so we use body scans and import object
files to check the accuracy of the final fit cross-referencing
we also have some conventional tailoring size charts with scanning points of
measure and they do differ so if you look at the two middle ones I suppose
probably create virtual me and also Clow3d those points of measure often relate
more to scanning date scanning systems than they do to conventional pattern
cutting we show our students how what the differences are and how to how to
overcome them
address body diversity to make sure that clothes fit all body shapes and it's a great tool to
ensure inclusivity we look at very curvy shapes we think about people who are heavier on their thighs
what i would really like to see is different cup sizes that that's my plea to flow 3d
but at the moment it's a great way for us to to test garments and on this slide you can see how
jen investigated different scanning technologies before editing the co3d avatar and next up this
was the next stage so you can see how she imported an object file into co3d and then adapted the
avatar she merged the body scan and the object file with the avatar to adapt a working model
to allow her to test the garment prior to the final digital fitting and this was to ensure
that the trousers that she made for her customer were really accurate
i love this tool i like the fact that you can also take object files into mixamo and articulate
them um and move them around it's a really great tool from a pattern cutting perspective
this is like digital to physical and this is where we're really focusing on on our course
students can investigate their own areas of research but we ensure that everybody can leave
the course understanding digital to physical and this is a typical
challenge we face a lot of times with the article writing process in our course so
this is a common practice in our course um a lot of times the feedback we get is from your
students and the most important thing is that we don't describe all the details of the project
in the summary of the presentation so that's not just so we want to plainly explain to you
that it's not just the details of the project it's the quality of the work that it is the type
as they are in the industry with smartphone technology you know these these garments
could be digitally tried on by customers and the lineups show the diversity of target customers too
so students have to consider the physical attributes to the population so for example
on the top line you've got sydney which is a more culturally diverse body type whereas on the bottom
because it's it's more korean they've gone for a more conventional body data the students did
investigate into city death body definitions you know city body measurements to look at the
difference in the balance of body types across the two cities but some of our students are really
interested in the metaverse and doing purely digital clothing for their masters of arts project
and for their career as well and they're free to explore this developing fashion market
we've had students doing metaverse using ai to generate digital fabric
and virtual fashion does have its place as you can see in some of the work shown in the
presentation however all our students have to create digital samples and test them in the
physical process for technical accuracy it's a way to fully understand how clothes are constructed
and how they function this is a raincoat um which is from the it's a colorway and it's created by
yaoyao for the sydney lineup from the previous slide and you can see how she's taken the avatar
out of the file so for example the factory
could investigate the inside of the garment yaoyao had really focused on digital clothing
before she came to us but and was quite shocked when i said i know you're going to have to make
a real garment um but we're looking we're working towards replacing physical product development and
sampling with digital alternatives because so much so much sampling is really wasted
and you know typically a brand will either work with a factory to produce a sample using
specification sheets or send physical garments to the factory but then the garments have got to be
made and then signed back to sent back to the brand to be signed off so there's a huge amount of um
physical waste happening and not all the processes can be released
replaced but we focus on creating accurate digital twins of the physical garments that you can see
here before cutting fabric and this is absolutely a work in progress but we haven't completely
sorted it out yet but um this is what we're asking students to create a garment that looks exactly
the same on the inside as the physical garment right down to for example the size of facings
and the iso stitch specifications um this slide shows the digital parker above and the physical
garment below and again this is the same piece from the previous slide you can see that the there
are differences
i mean this pattern was developed in close 3d it wasn't cut physically and then imported to sew up
sometimes our students work on the avatar we work in 3d and cut our patterns and flatten them
and do a hybrid 3d 2d pattern cutting method but this one i think she actually cut in 2d
flow and then she sewed it up but she still used clothes to develop the pattern
and you can see there were issues with accuracy so the physical one on the right hand side of the
bottom the hood's actually bigger than in the digital version but this was the first time that
yao yao had been required to match the digital digital to the physical accurately and cut the
pattern in close 3d and also it shows the importance of the accuracy of the physics
of digital materials which we hadn't this was very early in the course which is pretty much
the second term of when the course had been launched that we we started work using close 3d
and it was very new to us and to the students and in this slide you can sort of see that this
is a sample she's evaluating yinxi is evaluating and amending the pocket details we we create first
patterns using co3d we do lay plans we plot them to test the accuracy of the pattern cutting
but here you can see how we use 2d and 3d simultaneously um and it's really important
sometimes it's easier to make
an amendment in 2d and have it appear in 3d and sometimes you want to mark up on a 12 and then
appear directly in the pattern and that's a great thing to be able to do because typically what you
have to do when you're doing physical samples is you'll do the amendments on on on the physical
piece on the mannequin or on the model and then you've got to transfer that information direct
onto the pattern whereas this method means you can do it in 3d digitally and it translates onto
the pattern it's a really great i can draw all over my patterns and they will arrive
in my 2d pattern so i can do a rough mark and then i can do my lines in 2d and it looks much
more refined in 3d and here you can see the lay plan so yingxi was looking at her lay plan
and she was looking at the amount of fabric she got so the first lay plan she got 2.5
meters she'd obviously been very wasteful with her fabric clay and then in the second on the
piece on the right hand side you can see that she's actually saved half a meter i mean personally i
think we could have got it tighter but it's really good that she can see it straight you know
straight off and also then it can be exported into the bill of materials so we use the bomb tool as
well and then we transfer that information into zedonk which is an enterprise resource planning
software and then we transfer that information into zedonk which is an enterprise resource planning software
or an erp um it could also be trans translated you know transferred into a plm or a product
lifecycle management tool but that tends to be more at bigger scale erps are much better for
small scale which is why we teach those and here you can see that the information would go to tech
packs we are very interested in using close set but we haven't got that far yet um it's complicated
but we can only
deliver so much information to our students they can only absorb so much information within the
course because it's it's teaching them about product development manufacturing tracking
documentation as well so it is that in itself is difficult and then making sure that they can
do it digitally is another thing so um but you can see here that that the lay plan enabled her
to understand the rating
so next question you know many of the masters projects
currently use three three close 3d to prototype and present the process of translating digital
to physical fashion incorporating smartphone filters or websites um and i really wanted to
show you this um it's yao yao's master's project from 2021 she reverse engineered some garments
from the designer duo marknell and created 3d filters of the garments for her phone app concept
um the premise being that consumers can engage with the designers in the creation of their
clothing and in the near future they could also be able to try on digital garments
pretty much before we manufacture them if you can get enough traction with your customers to
digitally try on something before they order it as long as we've got the digital files in
place and the production in place we can then start to do production on demand you might think
of something like um unspun who are now doing denim in on the west coast of the states but then
exporting their files to manufacturers in turkey um for bespoke garments so on this slide this is
sort of like a snapshot of yaya's project and it was a collaboration as i said before with marknell
to translate specific garments from their spring summer 22 collection into 3d filters and snapchat
and yaoya graduated in 2021 and she's now the creative director for alterspace.com
a digital fashion platform working with designers to represent their physical garments digitally
so really interesting project that's come out of this and actually backed by farfetch
last year and they got funding as a as a startup and here you can see the process of creating
digital twins of the physical pieces and then the 3d filters in snapchat as i said yaya reversed
So she started with the physical pieces, and then it required her to import the patterns from the designers, the avatar meshes from Lens Studio into Cloth3D, adapt them using the avatar editor in Cloth3D, create the digital garments, export the avatars and the garments into Mixer mode to animate them or to rig them, and then back into Lens Studio.
It's a complex process, but it demonstrates how Cloth3D can be integrated into a digital workflow. It's not just a software that needs to be entirely, everything needs to be done entirely in Cloth3D. You can play around with it and use it in different software packages.
This is a project from this year's graduation group. Our students have a range of levels of skills in Cloth3D.
Some are interested in the visual media aspect.
Some want to experiment with mocap or motion capture software to bring their vision to life.
Yiran Shan recreated historical costumes from the tomb of Huang Shen from the Song Dynasty and recreated historical and cultural backgrounds in integrating 3D technology, such as Cloth3D and Unity3D.
And Yiran is class of 22. And here you can see how she integrated Cloth3D into the wider historical project and into the workflow.
And although this application
is not strictly fashion, the application of the concept is highly relevant to the fashion industry.
So the importance of understanding the physical properties and accurate garment construction enabled Yiran to understand the sophistication of Song Dynasty textile construction and choose the appropriate fabrics to recreate the garments.
As of course, we discussed in depth the physics, as well as the visual properties of digital materials.
You know, if the physics of the fabric
are not accurate, then the twirls and the patterns we create in Cloth3D won't be either.
And here Yiran discussed the structure of the physical fabrics before selecting digital counterparts, demonstrating her understanding of both the physical and digital fabric.
So I've put a link. This is, this is her Unity scenario. So she created all the scenes and then put the avatar, the motion capture, the clothing. She edited the avatar to the exact size and height of the
lady that she was recreate whose day in the life of shoes created.
And you can yeah you can see it here.
And it was a really nice little clip of of movement so Yiran did her own mocap and then she imported it in and made the piece.
These are the students past and present or have literally just graduated.
Good. Okay, fine.
So I will
will show you some films. This is Shenshan and she had a project called Pocket Mobile
Tailor. I'm a digital fashion designer and a problem solver. The fashion industry is
entering the 4.0 era. Emerging technologies are bringing a lot of innovation to the field
and are a great opportunity to change the environmental problems caused by current fashion
production and consumption. Beespoke Tailoring is a good example of sustainable fashion but
there are many limitations to this sector. This project combined the latest cutting-edge
technology with the traditional Beespoke model and developed a sustainable, cost-effective
platform that can implement remote Beespoke and meet the needs of a wider range of customers.
People can register for this platform in different roles. As you can see, the platform also serves
as a community. Here customers can find the designer they are interested in and click
on their profile.
Customers will need to create an avatar that will do a virtual fitting for them. There
are two options to choose from. If they are not too particular about their fit, they can
choose one of the default avatars. Otherwise, customers will need to take two photos of
their body as instructed. An artificial intelligence will generate a Beespoke avatar for them.
At the same time, they can start communicating these to the designer.
The designer will draw sketches for the customer and create a virtual garment based on their
Beespoke avatar. They can keep communicating through text box all the time with high flexibility
in design.
Once virtual garments are finished, customers can approve it through three different ways.
First is the 3D model, the second is AR, and the last one is video. After a customer is
satisfied with the virtual garment, they can start designing the Beespoke avatar. After
the customer is satisfied with the virtual garment, they can start designing the Beespoke
avatar. The physical garments will be made by manufacturers and delivered to the customer.
During the communication process, the real-time estimated price changes with every decision
making. The customer is required to pay a deposit before the designer works and a final
payment when the physical garment is ready. The customer's rating of the service is vital
for the designer to engage the next business. And by sharing their shopping experience with
the community, customers have the opportunity to modify their design in a better way. The
Customers have the opportunity to become influencers, thus attracting more people to use this platform to start their own creative journey.
This is going to be a wonderful platform for designers and payers to be a freelancer, fashionistas to show their strong personalities, independent designers to make samples for the new season, and for small manufacturers to expand their business.
This is also the practice for the industry 4.0 in the fashion field, which is conducted to a more sustainable development of this sector.